Please first read the paper for better understanding.

3 folders for simulations of each section:
- Neuron Bed simulation of a single strain;
- Co-propagation of two strains;
- Axon spreading dissemination between two clusters.

Each folder contains the necessary files to run a simulation. Use the Simul function to launch the simulation corresponding to the folder.
For example, while in one of the folders, use the command Simul('Params',1) in the Matlab console to get a video of the evolution of the simulation base on parameters Params.
Simulation time and outcome can greatly vary even while keeping the same parameters due to stochasticity.

The Simul(file,vid) function takes two inputs:
- file is the name of the .csv file containing the simulation parameters. For each folder, Params.csv is a parameters file with the right format that you can use as a starting point and modify;
- vid is a boolean variable to decide for video output as a .gif file. 0 means no video will be made.

The function outputs several graphs describing the evolution of the simulation as well as a .mat file and a video of the evolution depending on the value of vid.

Parameters:
- t_lim: time limit of the simulation.
- L: voxel size.
- div: domain size, the domain is a square grid of div*div voxels.
- s: maximum size of Bi assemblies.
- D0: diffusivity parameter.
- N_neur: number of neurons. For neuron bed and co-propagation simulations, number of neurons in the grid, needs to be a square number. In axon spreading simulations, 2 numbers corresponding to the number of neurons in each cluster.
- tpr: templating zone radius around the soma of the neuron. 1 for each cluster in axon spreading.
- uprr: UPR zone radius around the soma of the neuron. 1 for each cluster in axon spreading.
- uprt: UPR deactivation lag. 1 for each cluster in axon spreading.
- uprd: UPR density threshold, number of assembly inside the UPR zone required to trigger the UPR. 1 for each cluster in axon spreading.
- Kt: strain parameters, templating coefficients of A assemblies and Bi assemblies.
- Kc: strain parameters, reaction coefficients for decondensing and condensation of Bi assemblies.
- Kr: strain parameters, reaction coefficient for conformation change (A+B1->2B1) and catalytic depolymerization (A+B(i+1)->2A+Bi).
All strain parameters are doubled for co-propagation simulations. The first two lines correspond to strain 1 and the last 2 to strain 2.

Axon spreading specific parameters:
- init: decides at which cluster the simulation is gonna be seeded, cluster 1 or 2.
- N_ax: number of axons linking the clusters. First line is the number of axons from cluster 1 to cluster 2, second is cluster 2 to cluster 1.
- r_ax: width of the templating zone along the axon. One value for each cluster.

Output graphs:
Every simulation outputs four graphs describing the evolution of the system: quantity of A assemblies, quantity of B assemblies, average size of assemblies and percent of neurons with activated UPR.
In co-propagation simulations, A,B and average size graphs feature two curves, one for each strain.
In axon spreading simulations, the UPR graph features two curves, one for each neuron cluster. The first activation of the UPR of the group opposite of the inoculation can be used to track dissemination speed.

Output video:
In all videos, somas are represented as crosses in white when their UPR is inactive and pink while it is. In axon spreading, the axons are colored like the corresponding soma, indicating if the templating field is active or not.
In neuron bed and axon spreading, A assemblies are represented as green spheres while Bi assemblies are colored in a red to yellow gradient based on size.
In co-propagating simulations, strain 1 A are yellow and Bi red while strain 2 A are green and B blue.

For any inquiries, please send an email to basile.fornara@inrae.fr.

